847.920.4929

www.CharlesGrogan.com www.linkedin.com/in/charles-grogan/

# **Professional Summary**

Outgoing and experienced professional with 7+ years of management experience specializing in team management and strategic planning. Seeking to leverage servant leadership abilities and expertise to have a successful career in web development. Talents and skills include time management, critical inquiry and problem solving, and adaptability in rapidly changing environments that will prove essential as a successful web developer.

## **Technical Skills**

Client-Side Skills		Server-Side Skills	
• React/Redux	• Git	• NPM, Yarn	• JSON
• JQuery	• CSS	• Node.js	<ul> <li>Solidity</li> </ul>
• JavaScript/ES6	• HTML	• Express.js	<ul> <li>Mocha Testing</li> </ul>
• Materialize framework	<ul> <li>Webpack</li> </ul>	• Ruby on Rails	<ul> <li>Mongo Database</li> </ul>
• Heroku Deployment	• Bootstrap framework	• RESTful API	<ul> <li>MySQL (Sequelize)</li> </ul>

# **Projects**

#### Virtual Hostel - Full Stack Application

### Project Manager, Lead Design & Development

Virtual Hostel is designed for travelers to share their experiences with words and photos to a community of global travelers

• **Technologies**: React.js, Mongo database, Mongoose, RESTful API, JavaScript, JQuery, Bulma CSS framework, Passport login-in, Ajax, Axios, Git, HTML, & Heroku

### **Campaign Query** – Full Sack Application

#### Project Manager, Lead Developer

Campaign Query uses data visualizations to showcase campaign finance contributions from the 2016 election cycle

• **Technologies:** Node.js, Express.js, JavaScript, JQuery, amCharts, High Charts, MySQL, Sequelize, APIs, Ajax, CSS, HTML, Git, & Heroku

#### appDoption - Full Stack Application

#### Product Manager – Lead Developer

appDoption was built on the concept of love at first sight + every pet needs a forever home, regardless of age

• **Technologies:** JavaScript, JQuery, RESTful APIs (Petfinder API & HERE location API), Firebase database system, Materialize CSS framework, Git, & HTML

#### Friend Finder - Full Stack Application

Sole Developer

Friend Finder uses a sorting algorithm to pair matches based on survey results, as compared to other survey participants

• **Technologies:** Express.js, Node.js, JSON, RESTful API, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap front-end framework, CSS, HTML, & Heroku

#### SimpleBlog - Full Stack Application - Create, Read, Update, Delete

Sole Developer

SimpleBlog is a CRUD application that stores blog messages, enables comments, and secure log-in feature

• Technologies: Ruby on Rails, Ruby, SASS, Bootstrap front-end framework, HTML, & Heroku

#### **<u>bAmazon</u>** – Node.js Application

Sole Developer

bAmazon is a simulated store front application that tracks inventory and calculates price based on the quantity purchased

• Technologies: Node.js, NPM Inquirer, MySQL, NPM MySQL, Cli-Tables2

## **NYT Web Scraper** – Full Stack Application

Sole Developer

NYT Web Scraper is designed to search the archives at the New York Times and return stories pertaining to query

Technologies: JavaScript, JQuery, Ajax, API, Bootstrap front-end framework, CSS, & HTML

## **Experience**

# Teaching Assistant/Tutor – Web Development, Trilogy Education Chicago, Illinois

December 2018 - Current

- Code review and analysis in class assignments, homework, full stack applications, and group projects
- Collaborate with instructional staff to ensure the overall success of each student enrolled in the Northwestern University's Full Stack Web Development Coding Boot Camp
- Teach students best practices and methodologies how to find to problem solve, search for resources, and better understand documentation
- Coach students through complex problems using mechanisms to help them describe and fully understand the task at hand, as well as the tools necessary to overcome those challenge
- Topics covered in course include: JavaScript, React, Node.JS, Express.JS, MongoDB, JQuery, MySQL, HTML, CSS

## Sales Consultant, Enterprise Holdings Chicago, Illinois

October 2015 – June 2018

- Produced at 132% of my goal last quarter and 127% YTD, regarding sales and leads produced by my portfolio of accounts: credit union and strategic partners combined
- Strong analytical skills to track current methods and trends to create new strategies focusing on client retention, referral metrics, and 100% saturation into accounts
- Thrive on developing creative and strategic solutions, troubleshooting, and determining the root issue for my customers and accounts to drive revenue, customer satisfaction, and brand loyalty
- Lead product presentations, Q&A sessions, and post-sale follow-ups monthly
- Proficient in Salesforce with the ability to train others, navigate and analyze data

## Branch Manager, Enterprise Holdings Chicago, Illinois

February 2013 – October 2015

- Managed book of business consisting of nearly 70 national and local accounts, developed strategies to create growth, retention, and 100% business saturation
- Responsible for professional and personal advancement of nearly forty management trainees. Conducted weekly and monthly sales training, and created a positive work environment
- Increased branch profit by 80% in same period (\$95,000 to \$171,000 in total profit dollars) which was 60% above my goal credit to building strong relationships and strategic planning
- Supervisor of multiple locations, including O'Hare International Airport where I supervised for nearly 125 full time and part time employees

# General Manager, Union Station Restaurant Harrisonburg, Virginia

June 2010 – August 2012

- Oversaw the day to day operations of a two-hundred fifty seat restaurant with sales in excess \$2 million per year
- Created a positive, competitive, and thriving work environment through employee engagement, high levels of enthusiasm, and regular coaching / performance sessions
- Designed, developed, wrote, and maintained the original training manuals for all phases of the operation: Kitchen, Wait-Staff/Bar, and Catering

# **Education**

The DApper Network – Decentralized Application | Smart Contracts Ethereum Blockchain & Smart Contract Development Boot Camp

Graduated - November 2018

Northwestern University – School of Professional Studies Full Stack (MERN) Web Development Coding Boot Camp

Graduated - October 2018

Ohio University – College of Health and Human Services Bachelor of Science in Human and Consumer Sciences

Graduated - June 2010